Ong Guo Xiang

DESIGNER. ARCHITECT. RESEARCHER.

Email: ong.guoxiang@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ongguoxiang

Location:SingaporeGithub:https://github.com/gxiteSkype ID:live:ong.guoxiang_1Portfolio:https://gxite.github.io

I am a Research Assistant at the National University of Singapore, Department of Architecture since July of 2019. Prior to this, I had spent 2 years working as an Architectural Associate in Singapore, taking on both project management and design roles.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

National University of Singapore

Jul 2019 - Present

I process videos and images using Machine Learning models, performs spatial analysis.

Project: Measuring Physical Profile and Use of Park Connector Network with Deep Learning and Multi-Source Multi-Modal Data Analytics

- Set up and maintained the software and hardware environment to perform object and action recognition using Machine Learning models.
- Adapted open source research and wrote Python scripts to perform action recognition on large numbers of simultaneous detection on prerecorded video.
- Responsible for documenting all research related data and methodologies.

Architectural Associate

DCA Architects Pte Ltd Jun 2017 – Jun 2019

I have designed facilities for condominiums, managed construction contracts and worked on computational design on the sides.

- Worked as a Design Architect in collaboration with local consultant teams in Ho Chi Minh City. Generated building renders and visuals for all client presentations.
- Worked as a Project Architect for 2 Addition and Alteration works.
 Managed regulatory clearance, reviewed shopdrawings, provided design directions and visuals for presentations
- Developed computational design workflows within Rhinoceros 3D + Grasshopper and Revit + Dynamo

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Master of Architecture (2016-2017)

Bachelor of Arts (Hons. (2012-2016) Distinction), Architecture

SKILLS

CAD & Modelling

Rhinoceros 3D	(proficient)
Grasshopper	(proficient)
AutoCAD	(proficient)
Sketchup	(proficient)
Revit	(prior exp)
Dynamo	(prior exp)

Graphics & Rendering

(proficient)
(proficient)
(proficient)
(proficient)
(prior exp)

Programming Languages

Python	(proficient)
C++	(basic proficiency)
Java	(prior exp)

Others

ArcGIS	(basic proficiency)
Unreal	(prior exp)

LANGUAGES

English	(Native)
Mandarin	(Native)